So, Django, since this course is targeted towards more of an advanced beginner, we're
going to jump right into Django.
If you'd rather learn about Flask, you can watch the last chapter of the intermediate
Python course on front-end masters, or you can review the final exercise on the course website.
So, we're going to go ahead and grab the project code, instead of starting a Django
project from scratch, if you do want to start a new Django project from scratch,
I recommend that you follow the steps on the official Django tutorial for building your
first app.
That has everything that you need to start up a Django project, but for the time being,
we're going to work from a project that I have already created, so go ahead and see
into your home directory, and get clone this project right here, and then let's
see D into the practical blog directory.
One more thing, if you're not doing this in a new tab, make sure that you type D activate,
and clear out the current active virtual environment, we're going to create a new virtual
environment for this project, because it doesn't share any of the libraries that we
have been using in class before, and we want to keep everything separate.
That was already in the right place, so now you should have a directory that looks
something like this, and we're going to go ahead and create a new virtual environment,
and then we're going to use that Pipp install-r command to install what is in requirements
that TXT in it, so to make a new virtual environment, remember you do Python 3-m-vm-n,
and then we're going to source it, so source n-slashbin-slashactivate, and we'll see that
now I have my new virtual environment activated.
If I take a look at what is in requirements.txt, see that it is a file with just one line,
and it said the requirement is Django 3.1.2, so I can type Python-m-pip install-r, which
means install the requirements from this file, and pass in requirements.txt, and that's
going to go ahead and install Django.
While we're at it, we can also run Python-m-pip install-upgrade-pip to be on the latest version
of Pipp, so that we don't see this annoying warning anymore.
There are two things that we're going to need to do to get set up to run this web application.
We're going to need to prime our database by running a migrate command, and we're going
to need to run the server to make sure that our server has come up successfully.
So to prime the database, you're going to do Python-m-n-pip, along with the migrate command.
Managed up, he-y is a file that's automatically generated by Django, and has shortcuts
to a lot of the commands that you might want to run when working with a Django application.
You should see something like this.
Operations to perform, apply migrations.
Most of these four of these admin-off content type and sessions come baked into Django,
and then blog is the app that I've created.
So this goes ahead and creates all of the database tables that Django needs to operate.
In a file called db.sequallight3, that's because we're currently working with a local
SQLite database.
When you're working in production, you can move on to my SQL or Postgres or whatever
database you want to use.
Finally, we can run Python-mandaged.py-run server, and see if our server comes up successfully.
If it does, you should see it running at local host 8000, and when I visit that URL,
I'll see my Python blog no post yet come back later.
So I'm just going to give three or four minutes for folks to catch up with me and make
sure that they're able to start their Python server and see the same thing that I'm
seeing.
Instructions for that should be here.
I did notice one typo here, unfortunately, to make a new virtual environment, make sure
that you use Python 3 and not Python, and I will go ahead and fix that when I have a moment.